There's something wrong with Esther.
Orphan is a horror, thriller film directed by Jaume Collet-Serra.
After losing their baby, a married couple adopt 9-year old
Esther, who may not be as innocent as she seems.
Kate, played by Vera Farmiga.
John, played by Peter Sarsgaard.
Esther, played by Isabelle Fuhrman.
Sister Abigail, played by CCH Pounder.
Daniel, played by Jimmy Bennett.
Dr. Browning, played by Margo Martindale.
Orphan is a 2009 psychological slasher film directed by Jaume Collet-Serra
and written by David Leslie Johnson from a story by Alex Mace.
The film stars Vera Farmiga, Peter Sarsgaard, Isabelle
Fuhrman, CCH Pounder, and Jimmy Bennett.
The plot centers on a couple who, after the death of their unborn child,
adopt a psychopathic nine-year-old girl with a mysterious past.
The film is an international co-production between the
United States, Canada, Germany and France.
It was produced by Joel Silver and Susan Downey of Dark Castle Entertainment, and
Leonardo DiCaprio and Jennifer Davisson Killoran of Appian Way Productions.
Principal photography for the film took place in Canada, in the cities of St.
Thomas, Toronto, Port Hope, and Montreal.
Orphan was released by Warner Bros.
Pictures in the United States and Canada on July 24, 2009.
It was released in Germany on October 22, and in France on December 30.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and
grossed $78.8 million worldwide.
The film successfully launched its titular film series starring Fuhrman, including a prequel
titled Orphan: First Kill (2022), and its sequel titled Orphans in production.
The film explores themes of nun, deaf-mute, orphan,
troubled marriage, mischievous child.
The tone is intense and dark and mind_bending.